<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Engineer on Rafed Muhammad Yasir</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Software Engineer on Rafed Muhammad Yasir</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 21:07:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rafed.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Others</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/others/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:10:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/others/</guid><description>Writing I maintain a blog where I keep notes of experiences and everything that I have learned.
Read my tech blog at rafed123.github.io/devra/ Read my islamic blog at rafed123.github.io/islam/ Read my life blog at rafed123.github.io/blog/
Music I&amp;rsquo;ve been with music for a long time. I was home schooled in Rabindra Sangit and Nazrul Geeti for about 5 years. Later I joined Chayanaut. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t continue for long and had to dropout after 3 years.</description></item><item><title>Development Skills</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/skills/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:08:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/skills/</guid><description>In an interview I&amp;rsquo;d say that I&amp;rsquo;m a backend guy. However, I consider myself a generalist. I like to see the big picture of things and try to learn a bit of everything. That&amp;rsquo;s why I spend most of my time in learning other skills such as cloud, devops, machine learning, front end frameworks.
Backend Python: Nearly all my projects are done in python. I&amp;rsquo;m good with Flask and currently learning Django.</description></item><item><title>Software Projects</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 20:08:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the most noteable projects that I&amp;rsquo;ve done.
Pet projects There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of repositories in my Github/rafed123 that you can check out. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of them that I&amp;rsquo;m proud of:
8 puzzle (automatically solves a random puzzle using A* search) Ping and traceroute with icmp Competitive Projects Virtual Trial Room: A web based trial room that can fit dresses on a person standing in front of a camera.</description></item><item><title>Experience &amp; Achievements</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/experience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/experience/</guid><description>Professional Experiences Short course instructor, Institute of Information Technology - 2019-2020 Intern, FoxAI (MCC), Mohammadpur, Dhaka - Jan-June, 2018 Requirement Analyst, Glitra Bangladesh, Banani, Dhaka - March-May, 2017 Requirement Analyst, SoftCell Company Ltd, Banani, Dhaka - Oct-Nov, 2016 Achievements 2nd Runners up, CSE Fest - Inter university project show, Bangladesh University of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology (BUET) - 2018 2nd Runners up, Technival - Project showcasing, Khulna University of Engineering &amp;amp; Technology (KUET) - 2018 Joint Runners up, Cybernauts - Project showcasing, NSUCEC, NSU - 2018 Champions, Technovation - Hackathon, North South University (NSU) - 2018 Top 6, SCORE, ICSE, Montreal, Canada - 2018</description></item><item><title>Academics &amp; Publications</title><link>https://rafed.github.io/academics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:11:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://rafed.github.io/academics/</guid><description>Academic Qualifications MSSE (Masters of Science in Software Engineering), Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka - Enrolled BSSE (Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering), Institute of Information Technology, University of Dhaka - 2018 HSC (Higher Secondary Certificate), Notre Dame College, Dhaka - 2014 Publications GodExpo: An Automated God Structure Detection Tool for Golang; Rafed Muhammad Yasir, Moumita Asad, Asadullah Hill Galib, Kishan Kumar Ganguly, Md Saeed Siddik; 2019 IEEE/ACM 3rd International Workshop on Refactoring (IWoR@ICSE), Montreal, Canada</description></item></channel></rss>